Chicory Blue Press Records
Chicory Blue Press Records
1987-2011
Chicory Blue Press (Goshen, Conn.)
3.0 linear ft.
Founded by Sondra Zeidenstein, Chicory Blue Press of Goshen, Connecticut publishes poetry and short stories by women authors over the age of 60. Collection contains editorial files, correspondence, audio and video material; a number of published items were removed for separate cataloging.
2570336
Biographical History
Founded in 1987 by Sondra Zeidenstein, Chicory Blue Press of Goshen, Connecticut publishes poetry and short stories by women authors over the age of 60.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Chicory Blue Press Records contains correspondence, editorial files, subject files, and audio/video recordings. Most of the editorial files relate to anthologies edited by Sondra Zeidenstein. Some printed material has been removed for separate cataloging (see below).
Correspondence consists of letters, cards, notes and other items. Many are from other poets and authors. Correspondence relating to specific Chicory Blue titles may be found in the Editorial files for that title.
Editorial files contains correspondence, cover art, contract information, and other material relating to specific Chicory Blue titles. The Crimson Edge folders contain cover art and information on a number of Crimson Edge chapbooks.
Subject files relate to topics of interest to the press (e.g., older writers, age and creativity) as well as to the operation of the press itself (book fairs; publicity and promotion).
Audio and video contains audio and video recordings of prose and poetry readings, interviews with Zeidenstein and other authors and poets, and assorted other topics.
Arrangement of the Collection
Editorial files are arranged by title in order of publication. Correspondence files are alphabetical by name. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by various other subjects. Recordings are in no particular order.
Separated Material
Some published material (books and chapbooks) has been removed for separate cataloging. For a complete listing, please refer to and search for the phrase "Chicory Blue Press" appearing anywhere.
Subject and Genre Headings
Women Authors; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Publishing, printing and book arts; Arcana, Judith.; Golden, Alvia.; Kiefer, Rita, 1930-; Leontief, Estelle.; McCray, Carrie Allen, 1913-; Moore, Honor, 1945-; Nason, Tema.; Sanchez, Carole.; Swift, Joan, 1926-; Wagner, Anneliese, 1929-; Wong, Nellie.; Weinberger, Florence, 1932-; Zeidenstein, Sondra; Chicory Blue Press (Goshen, Conn.); Small Press Distribution (Firm); Older women.; Publishers and publishing.; Small presses -- Connecticut -- Goshen.; Short stories -- Women authors.; Women -- Poetry.; Women poets, American.; Women publishers -- United States.; Audiocassettes.; Correspondence.; Videocassettes.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to recordings requires advance notice to produce a working copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Sondra Zeidenstein, 2007, 2011.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - A-Z (Box 1)
  - Unidentified (Box 1)
- Editorial files
  - The Crimson Edge, 1996; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - A Detail in that Story, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Family Reunion, 2003; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Four Sublets, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Heart of the Flower, 1991 (Box 1)
  - The Love Word, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Memoir, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Resistance, 2003 (Box 2)
  - What If Your Mother, 2005; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - A Wider Giving, 1988; 4 folders (Box 2)
- Subject files
  - About the publisher (Box 2)
  - Age and creativity, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Book fairs, readings and exhibitions (Box 3)
  - Older writers (Box 3)
  - Publicity and promotion (Box 3)
  - SPD [Small Press Distribution] (Box 3)
  - Submission letters (Box 3)
  - Website (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Audio and video
  - Audiotapes, peotry readings, interviews with Zeidenstein and other writers and poets, etc.; 21 cassettes (Box 3)
  - Videotape, "Books and the Word," guest Sondra Zeidenstein, 1988; 1 cassette (Box 3)
- Printed material
  - Books, Removed for separate cataloging.
  - Crimson Edge Chapbook series, Removed for separate cataloging.